"All right, how is that?"
- You jackass sons of bitches!
- What the hell?
Don't think I don't know
what your game is.
What's wrong with you?
If I wasn't in a hurry,
I'd kick your lousy butts.
Hey, where you going?
Somebody stop him!
"Call 911!"
Good morning.
Hey.
Mr. Whitaker.
Mr. Whitaker!
Sir!
"His name's Charles Whitaker,
32, single."
He's a computer engineer
specializing in mapmaking.
This is his workplace in Houston
yesterday morning.
He's saying,
"Stop. Listen."
"Help me."
That was the last thing he said.
- I take it he's dead.
- Heart failure
Induced by a massive overdose
of prescription and illegal drugs.
Hm. So, he OD'd
and freaked out.
Why is the FBI
concerned with this?
He had sleeping pills,
crystal meth, MDMA
and horse tranquilizers
in his system
but, there were no pill bottles
or other drug paraphernalia
anywhere in his home.
He had
no drug history whatsoever.
His security profile indicates
no suicidal tendencies.
Accident or suicide is probable,
but murder is a possibility.
He was definitely trying to say
something before he died.
Why OD
and then decide to talk?
And why does he have
a security profile?
Aye, there's the rub.
That's why we're looking
into him at all.
Uh...
Oh. Wait here.
This room makes me feel like
I'm in an aquarium
and everyone's looking at me.
Mm. Well, you could
very easily feel like
they're all in the aquarium
and you're looking at them.
- What are you doing?
- I'm following the conversation.
The G-man says that I don't have
adequate security clearance
to work on the Whitaker case,
and Fischer is arguing.
Are you reading their lips?
Yeah, I would be if I didn't
have to answer inane questions.
Oh, okay, boss.
I'm not your boss.
Why would you say that?
It's just that sometimes now
you act like you are.
But we're equals, partners.
Okay, fine.
Just remember that.
I will remember that.
I... I will.
Oh, great. Now I don't know
what they decided.
- Hold on, sir.
- I'm done discussing this.
Jane, I'm Supervising Agent Daniels.
I'm in charge of security
clearance for the office.
I need you to leave immediately.
This briefing is classified.
Sir, I am in the process
of getting him clearance
from D.C. with an FD-258.
Jane is a consultant.
The FD-258 grants temporary
security clearance
to local officials in the event
of a terrorist attack.
- He hardly qualifies.
- You're right.
And, uh, if Whitaker was murdered
because of his highly sensitive
military work with the Pentagon
I shouldn't know
anything about that.
So, I'll happily leave.
Wait.
- What did you tell him?
- Nothing.
Who told you
that he works for the Pentagon?
And consider
your answer well.
- You did.
- Don't be absurd.
I've never seen you before.
No, but your presence here
told me
because you wouldn't be here
if he worked for, uh,
Pottery Shack or Pizza Barn,
would you?
- Excuse me?
- You're excused.
He's a little slow
on the uptake, this one.
Fischer, this is unacceptable.
- I apologize, sir.
- No, no. Hush. Don't apologize.
Don't take it out on her.
She didn't do anything.
Good morning, everybody.
What's all the rumpus?
I was just explaining
to Agent Fischer
that Mr. Jane doesn't have
security clearance
for the Whitaker case.
Oh. Well, problem solved.
I just talked to the Deputy Director
and, uh, he approved.
And you got the clearance
in writing?
Yes, sir.
Well, then,
I guess all this is on you.
Mm-hmm.
Carry on.
- Thanks, boss.
- No problem.
Congratulations, Jane.
You now have full security clearance.
Very few civilians get it.
That is awesome.
Thank you so much.
Oh, oh. Okay. Area 51.
What's the real story, huh?
Give me the skinny.
How long had your brother
lived here, Mr. Whitaker?
Uh, Curtis, please.
I believe it was
four years or so.
Do you think it was murder?
Uh, surely, it was suicide. How could
someone feed him all those pills?
Well, that's a good question.
- Any guesses?
- No.
Did your brother have a drug
problem, to your knowledge?
No, never. He was straight
edge his whole life.
But for heaven's sake,
why would anyone murder him?
Well, there's another
good question.
- Any guesses on that one?
- No.
I'm not sure I like your manner.
That is a very nice suit.
I always liked
the double-breasted, but it's...
Doesn't work on me.
I'm too short.
Did you get that in London?
- Yes, as a matter of fact.
- Mm.
You know, usually, uh, money
is either earned or inherited.
- Yours is both, isn't it?
- I suppose.
The family is established.
I'm in banking.
Bless you for your service.
And your brother drew maps,
nothing fancy.
Well, compared to the rest
of the family.
I did not say that.
My brother was extremely talented
but he went his own way.
My family values achievement.
Charles was a dreamer.
Uh, did you notice anything unusual
about your brother's behavior recently?
Full disclosure, there...
There was a dispute over some
money my grandmother left.
She'd wanted it to go
to the museum.
We were working it out.
I do know he was very excited
about some new project at work.
- Is this your newspaper?
- No.
- No?
Okay. You can go.
Thank you, Curtis.
We'll be in touch.
Thank you.
Good day to you.
Mm. Oh, he's a prime suspect.
Say again?
Oh, I was talking to my colleagues.
Bye, Curtis.
Thank you.
Well, he is, you know?
Beady eyes, a bespoke suit,
the feud over granny's will
Prime suspect.
I am gonna find a cup of tea,
sit down and relax
and read this newspaper.
I'll call you later.
But wait a second. We're going
to Cartesian, his employer.
Shouldn't you come with us?
Maybe later. I'll, uh...
I'll call you if I need you.
"If you ne..."
Hi. Avery Schultz.
I'm Gabriel's executive assistant.
I can take you to see him now.
Um, I'm sorry,
but you'll have to leave
your cellphones
and your guns here.
- If, if you have guns.
- I see.
We do, and, uh,
no, we're okay.
Oh, it's strict company policy,
for security reasons.
Sweetheart, we're FBI.
I'm not gonna give up
my Beretta
and my phone
contains protected data.
Our stuff stays with us.
Um, okay.
I'll... Let me just check
if it's okay.
You do that.
- You have a Beretta?
- Yeah. You?
I carry a Glock 26, but...
- Hello?
- Hey. Teresa?
Osvaldo Ardiles.
Long time, no see.
Hey, Ardiles.
How are you?
How's the private practice?
You know, more work, more money.
Can't complain.
How's the FBI?
Uh, it's the same money,
more work.
Great dental plan, though.
Hey, Teresa, you think, uh
we could meet for dinner tonight?
I have some business
to discuss.
Dinner? Well, I'm, I'm in Houston.
Oh, great.
I'm in Chicago.
Houston is no problem.
I'll take the jet.
You have a jet that you can use
to take me to dinner?
- What's the deal?
- I'd, uh...
- I'd rather discuss it in person.
- This is business, right?
It's not, you know, personal?
Oh, gosh, yeah.
No. Uh, strictly business.
Well, okay, then.
You're buying.
Deal.
That was weird.
Sounds intriguing.
Is there a problem?
- I hope not.
- Okay.
Gabriel said it's okay
to keep your things
so right this way.
It's really sad about Charles.
I saw him Sunday,
and he seemed totally chill.
What? What do you think
could have happened?
That's what we're here
to find out.
Um, this is our pre-viz department.
Pre-visualization.
- It, it's basically...
- We know.
Agents Lisbon and Fischer.
Hi. I'm Gabriel Quinn.
I run this place.
This is Leo Drembelas,
my general counsel.
Well, please.
Do you need anything else?
No, we're, we're fine, Avery.
Thank you.
Sorry about the security rigmarole.
We take every precaution we can.
So, how can we help you?
I understand you think
Whitaker was murdered.
We can't rule it out yet.
But suicide or an accidental
overdose is more likely, no?
Tell us a little bit
about Cartesian.
We develop tactical image visualization
for the armed forces.
Been around about six years.
The intelligence we develop
gets us close to a lot
of bad guys overseas.
Had Whitaker been working on
anything sensitive recently?
Ongoing projects
are strictly need-to-know
but assume that everything
we take on is sensitive.
- How did Whitaker get on here?
- He was a lovable goof.
Super-bright, uh, kind of a big kid
gave people nicknames.
He called me Quinner.
He put it on a t-shirt.
He was that guy.
Irritating sometimes,
but nobody disliked him.
We've pinged
the GPS in his car
and it told us
that he was here on Sunday
the day before he died.
A lot of your guys come in
on weekends?
Sure. Many. Yeah.
You don't take this job
because it's easy.
We're going to need to speak
with all of your employees
But we'd like to start with the guys
that were here on Sunday.
Of course.
I'll need to sit in,
as legal counsel.
Oh, sorry. Don't...
Hey, Cho, finished grilling
the locals?
'cause, uh, I think
I may have a lead.
Sunday. Yeah.
I was fixing some resolution issues
on our dynamic terrain simulator
uh, but...
- Did you talk to Whitaker?
- Sure.
Yeah, you know,
"Hey. How's it going?"
- Like that.
- How did he seem?
He was one of those guys...
He was quiet or loud.
Sunday he was quiet,
like, thinking.
His brother said that he was
excited about a new project.
- A new project?
- Why is that strange?
There was none.
Uh, he was stuck on this massive
geo-spatial analysis report.
It's the last thing in the world
you'd be excited about.
And that's all we're at liberty
to divulge about that.
And did you see Whitaker
talk to anybody else on Sunday?
Yeah, he asked Hagen
a lot of questions.
Martin Hagen,
our military liaison.
And what did Whitaker say
to you?
He wanted to know whether
any of the secret technologies
developed here
has shown up in foreign hands.
- And what did you say?
- The answer is yes
but there's always
a certain amount of leakage.
And did he tell you
that he thought
somebody inside the company
was stealing data?
- He didn't say that.
- But you got that impression?
With all due respect,
Mr. Hagen's opinion is not germane.
Let me point out, agents
there is zero evidence
of a security breach here.
We cannot even be sure
a murder was committed.
Let us keep this matter
in proportion.
- This is a lead?
- It, it's a coded message. See?
That says what?
I have no idea.
I thought you were good at code-breaking.
Yeah, that's not the point.
The point is
- there's a coded message here.
- Or doodles.
Oh, come on.
You know, you...
you've read crime novels.
You, you wanna communicate
with someone
but not be seen with them
then you put a message
in a newspaper
and you leave it
in a public place.
- You think Whitaker was a spy.
- No. I think he found a spy.
He saw someone leave this paper,
and he intercepted the drop.
We need to find out when and where
he found this newspaper.
Espionage is a big leap from
doodles in some old newspaper.
Remember, it's still perfectly possible
that Whitaker killed himself.
The company Whitaker worked for
did some top-secret stuff.
His apartment looked like
it was decorated by an 8-year-old.
He was naive, inquisitive,
very clever
and he had one copy of a very serious
newspaper he never read
which, as you can see,
is faded and stained
as though it's been left
outside someplace.
Now he's dead.
Okay, I have the security
footage from Cartesian.
The newspaper came out
last Friday
so that's our starting point, obviously.
Whitaker arrives at work
at 8:45.
No paper visible.
At 1:15, he comes out,
probably for lunch.
No paper.
Aha!
He comes back at 2:10
with a newspaper.
The financial record
which he puts away inside his jacket
before entering the building.
Aha.
Which way
does he come from?
We'll retrace his steps.
- Uh, he came from the south.
- Thanks, Wylie.
South.
How far south do we walk?
Eventually we'll come to a small park
with a bench under a fig tree.
Why is that?
Bird poop and tree sap,
with a faint figgy note.
No, I'm good.
Ah, look. Ficus Rubiginosa.
It's a fig tree.
Okay. Good call, maybe.
And...
Yep.
That's our bench.
What, you don't know the Latin
for bench?
No need to be snippy
just because I was right.
I said good call already.
What now?
Well, it's too late today.
We come back tomorrow
at lunchtime
leave the newspaper,
see who picks it up.
- If someone picks it up.
- Oh, someone will.
I suspect the other spy
comes by once a day
to see if there's been
a message left.
He'll keep coming until he finds
a newspaper to pick up.
Or Whitaker just OD'd.
Any other brilliant breakthroughs?
Otherwise, I'm gonna hit the gym.
- You should hit the gym.
- Yeah.
- Jane?
- "Lisbon?"
Where are you?
"I'm on the scent of murder
like a bloodhound."
We just questioned the staff.
Apparently, the day before he died
Whitaker was asking people
about industrial espionage.
Yeah, I'm a little ahead of you
on that one.
You broke into my car.
I entered your car
without your knowledge.
But the good news is,
tomorrow at around 2:00
this case will be cracked.
- You sound awfully sure of yourself.
- Always.
So, what's going on tonight?
Tonight I plan on painting
Houston red.
Mm. Where's Cho?
Arm-wrestling with some heavy objects
at the gymnasium.
Oh, I just want room service.
I happen to have a date.
Sorry? A date?
What, like I couldn't possibly
have a date with somebody?
You have a date in Houston?
Yeah. Remember Osvaldo Ardiles?
Ardiles? Two words:
Tassled Loafers.
- Uh, he's not a bad-looking man.
- Tassled Loafers?
Oh, wait.
Hold on. Back up.
You said you already
solved the case.
Are you gonna tell us how?
Oh, ask him,
and he won't tell you.
Pretend you're not interested,
and he might.
I'm not even gonna try.
Uh, I... I'm sorry. You...
You said, uh, "date"
and then the subject changed.
Yeah, okay. It's not exactly a date date.
It's a business thing.
He is flying in
on a private jet from Chicago.
Wow, that's very impressive. Why?
I don't know.
I'll find out tonight.
So, how's life
in San Francisco?
Oh, it's good.
I'm barely there.
This case has me traveling
half the month.
- Big case.
- Yeah, defending a cellphone company.
Competitor says my client
stole their phone design
so my client's looking at a hundred
million dollars in legal bills
give or take.
I'd be happy to take some.
Listen, the, um...
The thing is
several times now
in meetings, uh, my phone gets hot
even though I haven't used it
you know, like it's been on
the whole time
like, like somebody hacked it
and used it to listen in on me.
Ardiles, you flew here
all the way from Chicago
to tell me
your phone gets hot?
Yeah.
What is it
you're not telling me?
Nothing. Nothing verifiable.
Go on.
Last couple months
I just get this bad,
bad feeling.
You know,
like somebody is watching me
somebody malicious,
who really doesn't like me.
You ever get that feeling?
I'm sure your company has
good detectives on retainer.
Yeah, but I can't go to them
'cause I don't think it has
anything to do with my business.
Why not?
Uh, you said it was a big case.
No, this is not the way
the other side plays.
This is personal, all right?
But I got no...
I got no real proof.
You know,
I sound like a crazy person.
This is not
in my head, Teresa.
Come on.
You know me.
There is something going on
and I need the advice
of a detective
that I can trust 100%.
As it happens, I know
exactly what you should do.
Uh, when you go back
to San Francisco
call Wayne Rigsby
and Grace Van Pelt.
They, they're in the bay area
and what you need
is what they do now.
Digital security.
They're good.
If there's anything going on,
they'll find out.
Drink up.
Hot phones.
"He seemed a bit jumpy.
But he was always a little jumpy."
I think he might be losing it,
but you never know.
Maybe it really is bugged.
Anyway, Rigsby and Van pelt
could use the business.
Maybe he just wanted a date
with you.
- Have you considered that?
- Please stop.
Ardiles. He always had
a crush on you.
It's 2:23.
This is a waste of time.
Your theoretical spy
isn't showing up.
- You have to have patience, Lisbon.
- I'd rather have coffee.
There's a place over there.
You want anything?
- I'm good.
- Okay.
Uh, excuse me, sir.
Do you happen to have the time?
- You have a watch.
- Yeah, I, I forgot to wind it.
Uh, it's almost 2:25.
- Thank you.
- No problem.
- Did you take my phone?
- What?
I can't...
I can't find my phone.
No, I didn't take anything
from you.
- Then where is my phone?
- How would I know?
Hey, hey, whoa, whoa.
Wait a minute.
Help. Police! Police!
- This man stole my phone.
- What's going on?
He stopped me
and he asked me the time
and he just snatched my phone
right out of my hand.
- He's a thief.
- He is lying.
He stopped me,
he asked for the time, and I...
- Sir, sir, is that true?
- No, sir.
He stopped me,
he asked for the time, and...
- This man is crazy.
- Uh, liar.
Could you call my phone, please?
- Call.
- 555-0189.
Yes. There. Thank you.
That's my phone.
That's my ringtone.
Very good.
You tricked me.
- Yeah. Thank you.
- Very good. Very good.
Oh, you, you're gonna let him
just walk away?
Sir, sir, I didn't tell you
you could leave.
- What's happening?
- A whole lot is happening.
So, Mr. Hassan Zarif,
you're in quite the pickle.
Please, before you waste
valuable breath
I will not boondoggle
with the FBI.
what do you want to know?
How long have you been buying
intelligence from inside Cartesian?
Uh, a year, about.
- From who?
- I do not know.
My client arranged the first purchase.
And who's your client?
They're far away abroad
and very powerful and very rich.
And I will never tell you
their names
Even if you torture me.
Mm. Okay.
So, tell us about the seller
inside Cartesian.
I know nothing. I mean,
all contact is anonymous.
When the seller has a file to sell,
he drops a newspaper at the park.
We have a simple code.
This one says
"same price as last time."
Then what happens?
Um, we have another spot
in the same park
for the actual exchange.
I leave cash.
The seller picks it up
leaves a flash drive
with the data.
I, I paid $475,000 in total.
Ouch.
But you have no idea
who this person is?
No, sir, I do not.
- Do you know a Charles Whitaker?
- No.
He worked at Cartesian
died two days ago
heart failure.
May he rest peacefully.
- What of it?
- We think he was murdered
either by your client or you
or whoever you're buying from.
I see.
- That puts a different complexion.
- Yeah.
Very sad.
Uh, my client
did not kill this person.
I assure you.
Uh, the arrangement was too lucrative.
I, I did not do it
for the same reason. I mean
you must believe me.
Yes, we must.
The spy inside Cartesian
is the killer
and I have an excellent plan
for their capture.
Which is what?
Well, our mystery spy
had something to sell.
That's why they left a newspaper
but Whitaker screwed it up.
So they still have
something to sell.
And they don't know
we intercepted their buyer.
Exactly. They'll try again.
They just need to be lulled
into a false sense of security.
And how do we lull them
like that?
We need to arrest
someone else
and charge them
with Whitaker's murder.
We can't arrest people
under false pretenses.
- We can't?
- No.
- Why not?
It's illegal.
Oh. Well, that's a problem.
I guess we need to think
outside of the box.
That's always a bad sign.
- Relax.
- I am relaxed.
Really? I've seen rodeo bulls
more relaxed.
Okay, I'm not relaxed.
You're acting like you used to act
in the early days
and it makes me nervous.
- How did I act in the early days?
- You were crazy.
Oh. I'm not anymore.
- You're not?
- Nope.
Then what are you?
I'm fine.
I know how to calibrate
these things.
Ah. Mr. Whitaker.
Mr. Jane.
How can I help you?
The question is,
how may I help you?
I don't follow.
Well, as you can imagine,
Mr. Whitaker
I've been watching you
very hard.
Very, very hard.
I know what you did.
Oh, yeah, I know.
What do you mean?
What did I do?
You want me to say it
out loud?
Most people would pay me
to keep quiet.
Are you asking me
for a bribe?
How dare you?
- Oh, my god!
- Is that gonna do?
Sir, you're under arrest
for battery.
Samuels, call someone!
This is ridiculous.
What is happening?
- Lawyer.
- Curtis.
Call me Mr. Whitaker.
And I want to speak with my attorney.
Mr. Whitaker,
you don't need a lawyer.
Damn right.
Any clown on the street
could tell you
that battery charge won't stick.
I was grossly insulted
by that, that man
- and I was falsely arrested.
- You're right.
It was a pretext
to get you off the street
- in a conspicuous way.
- What?
I'm very sorry for any trouble
that you've been caused.
- We need your help.
- My help with what?
We think that Charles
was hunting for a spy at work.
Hunting for a spy?
Charles made maps.
Right, but the company
that he worked for
they're a Pentagon subcontractor
Battlefield apps.
Somebody was stealing
and selling sensitive military data.
Charles caught on to it.
Sounds exactly like
the kind of half-baked fantasy
Charles would have cooked up.
Except it's true.
You're saying my brother got
killed for rooting out a spy?
- Yes.
- And now you need my help?
We need his killer to feel safe
enough to make one more deal.
We need them to think
no one's looking at them
so we need someone else
to look at
someone plausible.
- Me.
- Exactly.
That's an absurd idea.
Is this really
how the FBI operates? Really?
- We're a specialized unit.
- What if I say no?
Then we'll press
the battery charges.
But you just admitted
those were bogus.
Only to you.
Either way,
you're staying here.
This is outrageous.
- I swear, my attorneys will...
- Curtis.
This isn't about you.
This is about national security
and justice for your brother.
So deal with it.
As a courtesy, we wanted to update
you on the Whitaker case.
We saw the news.
You arrested his brother?
Yes. Uh, we haven't charged him yet,
but soon.
There was a dispute over
some money that a relative left.
Curtis got greedy,
it looks like.
I didn't know there was money
in the family.
Several million.
Is there anything else
you need from us, agents?
No, no. We just wanted you
to hear it from us.
And we know Charles had a lot
of friends in the building.
I just can't believe it.
It's so sad.
It's very sad,
but family feuds run deep.
We see this sort of thing
all the time.
Yeah, of course.
It's just... Wow.
Well, have a safe trip
back to Austin.
And you haven't made any phone calls
since the incident?
On my cell? No.
I bought a burner.
Can you believe that? Me in some grimy back
alley buying a prepaid phone
from a kid
who probably stole the thing.
Oh, that was smart. If, in fact, your
digital life has been compromised.
You two can do this?
You can take over someone's phone?
Yeah.
'cause whoever's doing this
to me, I wanna nail them.
I wanna destroy them.
I'm sorry.
This one will not go to sleep.
No, I'm, uh, I'm sorry.
I got excited.
Look, we can't wage war
on whoever bugged your phone.
If you were bugged.
That's just not a service
that we provide.
I understand.
We'll start
by looking into your phone
and as soon as we know anything,
you'll know.
- Thank you.
- And you understand the pricing schedule?
Yep, I do. It's no problem.
Do whatever it takes.
Look, I'm scared.
And I want this fixed.
All righty, then.
We'll be in touch.
Wow.
This is juicy.
But like Lisbon said,
he seemed a little out there.
"What you think
he's imagining this stuff?"
"Well, I hope not."
"I mean, I hope he's not in danger
or anything."
"But this could be a big case
for us."
"It would be too bad if it were just
a faulty phone and paranoia."
"2:11. Still no action
at the park benches."
"No sign of anyone approaching
from either side of the Plaza."
No kidding.
Maintain radio silence
unless you have something to say.
"Yes, sir."
You tell 'em, Cho.
Mm. This is like
a stakeout of old.
You, skeptical and grumpy.
Me, confident, cheerful.
You're only being cheerful
to irritate me.
I'm cheerful because
I get to sit here with you
in this park
on such a beautiful day.
Son of a gun.
It's Avery Schultz.
Gesundheit. Is that a real person?
It's the CEO's secretary.
"She's sitting on the target bench."
"She's made the drop."
"Okay, we've seen enough.
Move in."
"Copy that."
"Movin' in."
- "Do you see her?"
- "Yes."
- "Stay on her."
- "Copy that."
- "She's on the move."
- "Go, go, go, go. Let' go."
Stop! FBI!
FBI! Out of the way!
Everyone, move, move!
Stop!
"She's cutting through the fountain."
"Get on the other side."
- Hold it right there!
- Avery Schultz.
You're under arrest.
"Subject is contained. I repeat,
subject is contained."
Come on out of there.
I would have never thought
it was her.
Huh. Really?
You surprise me.
You normally have
such good people instincts.
- I do?
- No, I'm kidding.
Well, I was kidding
that I was kidding.
You have very good
people instincts.
It's just your people skills
are a little...
- Oh, you're hilarious.
- Yeah.
Nicely done, Cho.
You look great in that hat.
We searched your apartment.
Some nice shoes,
but otherwise kind of Spartan.
Your buyer says he paid you
almost $500,000.
My mom has medical issues.
And I have drug issues,
to be frank.
So the money goes.
How'd you get started
in the espionage business?
My dad was a big-deal
currency trader until he went bust.
We lost everything.
Five years ago,
he killed himself.
I was desperate
so a man reached out to me
on the internet
said he was a friend
of my father's
said he was a journalist
said he would pay me for gossip
from the high-tech world.
- It grew from there.
- And what's the name of this man?
Oh, he doesn't exist.
He is a crime syndicate
in Russia someplace, I think.
By the time I realized that,
it was too late.
I had gone too far already.
When I said I wanted to stop
they threatened to tell
Cartesian what I had been doing
so, I had to keep doing it.
Then that idiot
started following me.
Charles Whitaker.
I had a feeling
someone was watching.
"But you do, don't you?"
"When you're doing stuff
like that, you get paranoid."
"So I forced myself
to ignore the feeling."
"Big mistake."
"We were both in the office
on Sunday."
He told me he knew
what was going on.
Avery, we work for the Pentagon.
What you're doing?
They call treason.
- You have to stop.
- Treason?
Charles, it's a game.
It's something we do for fun
me and bunch of friends
from college.
We've been doing it for years.
It's like a scavenger hunt.
- So, you're not selling stuff?
- Me? A spy? Really?
No.
Charles.
It's just a game.
"But I knew that lie
was not gonna hold him for long."
"I knew
I had to keep him quiet."
So I went to see him early Monday.
Hey.
- Can we talk?
- Sure.
Come in, I guess.
"I put enough drugs in him
to kill a horse."
He didn't look it,
but that guy was strong.
Shame you had to kill him.
Hey, you're a cop.
You're not a judge.
Don't judge me.
I had no choice.
- No, you had a choice.
- Yeah
I could have given up.
But I don't give up.
And that is a virtue.
It's not a sin.
- "Wayne?"
- Hey, Grace.
I can't contact Ardiles.
His office hasn't heard from him
since Friday.
Can't exactly call the guy and tell him
his cell phone's been bugged.
"Can you ping his cellphone,
try and figure out where he is?"
Sure thing.
1313 Owens street.
Yeah, got it.
Hey, are you gonna be home
for dinner?
"Uh, yeah, sure."
Wait. Are you at
that dirty taco truck?
I can literally hear you
trying to think up an excuse.
No. That's the sound
of me eating a taco.
Salad tonight. I promise.
I love you. Bye.
Hey, baby.
What are you doing?
The National Intelligence
Distinguished Service Medal
for your brother's selfless contributions
to the intelligence community.
You should be very proud of him.
Now we'll get you
to the presentation room, okay?
Agent Fischer, you coming along?
Cho and Lisbon
are already there.
- Uh, I'll be along in a moment, sir.
- Okay.
Okay, he's gone.
- Scaredy-cat.
- Just being considerate.
Seeing me again
would have spoiled his big day.
Oh, by the way, I just, uh...
I found the trailer I was looking for.
You can have
any vehicle you want
and you choose
an airstream trailer?
But that, it's for
an old retired couple.
I think it's an elegant solution.
An office and a vehicle in one.
Could change my entire approach
to solving crimes.
I won't fight you on that.
Hey, what did you say to him
that made him so angry that he hit you?
Oh, I have a foolproof line.
Foolproof.
1313 Owens street. Okay.
"This is Wayne.
Please leave a message."
Wayne, uh, call me back
as soon as you get this.
Actually, don't call me back.
Just, uh, meet me at the corner
where you had lunch.
I'll be waiting for you.
Don't worry. It's not the kids.
"Ardiles isn't the only one
being bugged. It's all of us."